Captioning Provided By:
Mtv networks
字幕提供者：
音乐电视网
Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
I can't  hear  you.
我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain.
孩子们：
是的，是的，船长。
♪ Ohh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids: ♪ Spongebob Squarepants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
队长：♪ 吸水性的，黄色的
他是多孔的 ♪
Kids: ♪ Spongebob Squarepants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ If nautical nonsense
be somethin' you wish ♪
船长：♪ 如果是航海方面的废话
成为你所希望的那样 ♪
Kids: ♪ Spongebob Squarepants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
船长：♪ 然后降落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
Kids: ♪ Spongebob Squarepants ♪
孩子们：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Ready? ♪
队长：♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
All: ♪ Spongebob Squarepants ♪
全部：♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ Spongebob Squarepants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
Captain: ♪ Spongebob
Squarepants ♪
队长：♪ 海绵宝宝
方裤♪
Mm, this is how to live,
isn't it, my friend?
嗯，这就是生活，
不是吗，我的朋友？
You said it, buddy.
你说过了，伙计。
He's amazing.
他太棒了。
I'll say.
我会说。
Whoa.
哇哦。
Whoo-hoo-Hoo!
呼呼呼！
Who is that guy?
那个人是谁？
That's Larry the Lobster.
那是龙虾拉里。
He's like livin' large.
他就像生活得很大一样。
What's your secret, Larry?
你的秘密是什么，拉里？
Well, you gotta
take risks.
好吧，你必须
承担风险。
Live on the edge.
生活在边缘。
All: Ooh...
全体：哦...
And you can't, uh...
而你不能，呃...
And you can't...
而你不能...
And you can't live
like these two.
而你却无法活下去
就像这两个。
Just look at 'em.
看看他们。
Spineless...
没骨气...
Weak.
虚弱的。
Afraid of their own shadows.
害怕自己的影子。
Pathetic.
可怜的。
Larry, how can
they redeem their
worthless lives?
拉里，怎么可以
他们赎回他们的
生命毫无价值？
I'll tell you how?
我来告诉你怎么做？
By living each day
as if it were their last.
通过过好每一天
就好像这是他们的最后一次。
How do we do that?
我们该怎么做呢？
By living
like me, Larry.
通过生活
像我一样，拉里。
But what's that have...
但那有什么...
Uh-buh-Buh-Buh.
呃，呃，呃，呃。
By livin'...
like Larry.
靠着活着...
像拉里.
Livin' like
Larry.
生活就像
拉里.
Livin' like Larry.
像拉里一样生活。
Livin' like...
♪ Larry ♪
生活就像...
♪ 拉里 ♪
This is bogus.
这是假的。
What's that, Pat?
那是什么，帕特？
Spongebob, these are
the best years of our lives
海绵宝宝，这些是
我们生命中最美好的年华
and you wanna waste
them blowing bubbles?
而你想浪费
他们吹泡泡吗？
We should be
living in the moment.
我们应该
活在当下。
We ought to be
living like Lar...
我们应该是
像拉尔一样生活...
This is it, Spongebob.
就是这样，海绵宝宝。
This is where we redeem
our miserable lives.
这就是我们赎回的地方
我们悲惨的生活。
It's time to start...
是时候开始了...
livin' like Larry!
像拉里一样生活！
Wah-hoo!
哇呼！
Whoa.
哇哦。
Ah-ah-Whoo!
啊啊啊呼！
Wha-ha, yee-hah, hee-hee!
哇哈哈，嘿嘿嘿！
Wha-hoo!
哇呼！
Hey, Spongebob?
嘿，海绵宝宝？
Spongebob?
海绵宝宝？
I'm living like Larry.
我过着像拉里一样的生活。
whoo-hoo.
呼呼。
where were you, Spongebob?
海绵宝宝，你在哪里？
It was awesome.
太棒了。
Hey, Patrick,
where you going?
嘿，帕特里克，
你要去哪里？
To live, my friend.
为了生活，我的朋友。
We...are going to live.
我们……要活下去。
This is gonna be
the most fun yet.
这将会是
最有趣的了。
I don't know
about this, Patrick.
我不知道
关于这一点，帕特里克.
You must defeat
your reason
你必须击败
你的理由
before you can start...
在你开始之前...
...livin' like Larry.
...像拉里一样生活。
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
Spongebob!
海绵宝宝！
...This is it!
...就是这样！
...oww!
...哇！
Ahh!
啊！
SpongeBob: ♪ Dee, dee-dee,
doo, Dee-dee-Dee ♪
海绵宝宝：♪ 迪伊，迪迪，
嘟，迪迪迪♪
♪ Livin' like Larry ♪
♪ 像拉里一样生活 ♪
♪ doo-doo, Doo-dee-Dee,
livin' like Larry ♪
♪ 杜杜，杜迪迪，
像拉里一样生活 ♪
♪ Livin' like Larry ♪
♪ 像拉里一样生活 ♪
come on, Spongebob,
what are you waiting for?
来吧，海绵宝宝，
你还在等什么？
Let's go.
我们走吧。
But Patrick,
where are we going?
但是帕特里克，
我们要去哪里？
Patrick: Just you wait.
帕特里克：你等着吧。
It's the ultimate.
这是终极的。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
And wait'll you
see the best part.
等等你
看到最好的部分。
Patrick: Hey, you guys!
帕特里克：嘿，你们！
I don't know, Patrick,
this looks really dangerous...
我不知道，帕特里克，
这看起来真的很危险......
Here's to livin' like Larry.
像拉里一样生活。
Well, wait
a minute, Patrick.
好吧，等等
等一下，帕特里克。
I think you're
missing the point.
我认为你是
没有抓住要点。
Livin' like Larry doesn't mean
throwing caution to the wind
像拉里一样生活并不意味着
不顾一切
and risking everything
on a stunt that will
cost you your life.
并冒着一切风险
的特技表演
让你付出了生命的代价。
Uh... Don't you
mean cost us
呃...你不是吗
我们的平均成本
our  lives, Spongebob?
我们的生活，海绵宝宝？
No, Patrick,
I mean your life.
不，帕特里克，
我指的是你的生活。
I'm not going.
我不去。
Oh, I see.
我懂了。
And that's your final
word on the subject?
这就是你的最终结局
关于这个主题的词？
Um-hm.
嗯嗯。
I feel sorry for you.
我为你感到难过。
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
Oh-ho-Ho!
噢-嗬-嗬！
I wonder how Patrick's
doing with his livin'
like Larry thing?
我想知道帕特里克怎么样
他的生活
像拉里的事？
Patrick: Spongebob?
帕特里克：海绵宝宝？
Spongebob!
海绵宝宝！
You were right, Spongebob.
你是对的，海绵宝宝。
I went to far.
我走到了很远的地方。
: I went too far!
: 我太过分了！
Oh, it's ok, buddy.
哦，没关系，伙计。
I think you've learned
your lesson, hm?
我想你已经学会了
你的课，嗯？
: uh-huh.
: 嗯嗯。
Gang Member: Don't make
us come in there, kid.
团伙成员：别做
我们进来吧，孩子。
Now you just let me handle
those guys out there.
现在你让我来处理
外面的那些人。
Gentlemen, gentlemen.
先生们，先生们。
SpongeBob: I know that
you might be angry
海绵宝宝：我知道
你可能会生气
with my friend
for his shenanigans
和我的朋友
为了他的恶作剧
but you are not
the only victim.
但你不是
唯一的受害者。
His reckless thrill
chasing has left him
他的鲁莽的兴奋
追逐已离他而去
a hollow shell
of his former self.
一个空心的壳
他以前的自己。
Just look.
看看吧。
So let me assure you...
所以让我向你保证...
his days of living
in the moment are over.
他的日子
此刻都结束了。
...Can you not forgive him
for whatever he did?
……你能不能原谅他
无论他做了什么？
Sure, pal... Sure.
当然，朋友……当然。
By the way, what  did  he do
that made y'all so cranky?
顺便说一句，他做了什么
这让你们这么暴躁？
He knocked over our motorcycles.
他撞翻了我们的摩托车。
Bah.
呸。
So scared... Adrenaline pumping.
太害怕了……肾上腺素激增。
Spine tingling.
脊椎发麻。
Endorphins rushing.
内啡肽涌动。
I've never felt so alive!
我从来没有感觉如此充满活力！
Oh, yeah, baby, yeah!
哦，是的，宝贝，是的！
This is what Patrick
was talking about.
这就是帕特里克
正在谈论。
This is really
living in the moment.
这真是
活在当下。
Whoo-yeah!
呼-耶！
This is life!
这就是生活！
Whoo, whoo!
呼呼！
Oh, yes, whoo!
哦，是的，哇！
Now I am really
现在我真的是
livin' like Larry.
像拉里一样生活。
Whoa!
哇！
Patrick: Are you sure
about this, Spongebob?
帕特里克：你确定吗？
关于这个，海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob: Oh, come on,
Patrick, what happened
to being in the moment?
海绵宝宝：哦，来吧，
帕特里克，发生了什么事
活在当下？
I don't know, Spongebob.
我不知道，海绵宝宝。
This looks pretty dangerous.
这看起来相当危险。
Yeah, yeah,
you said it, buddy.
是啊，是啊，
你说过了，伙计。
Now we're really
livin' like Larry.
现在我们真的
像拉里一样生活。
Well, will you look at that?
嗯，你会看一下吗？
...Now there's two guys
who know how to live.
......现在有两个人
谁知道如何生活。
Prepare for
countdown.
准备
倒计时。
I'm proud of them.
我为他们感到骄傲。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
With that angle of trajectory
有了这个轨迹角度
they'll land right in...
Ripper's Reef.
他们将立即降落在...
开膛手礁。
They'll be ripped to shreds.
他们会被撕成碎片。
Wait, don't do it, stop!
等等，别这样做，停下来！
SpongeBob:
Three, two, one.
海绵宝宝：
三、二、一。
Liftoff.
升空。
Drat.
德拉特。
Whoo!
呼！
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
...whoo-whoo-Whoo.
...呼-呼-呼。
Ooh?
哦？
Whoa...
哇...
whoa...
Look, guys, my advice wasn't
meant to be taken literally.
听着，伙计们，我的建议不是
从字面上理解。
I meant to live
life to the fullest
我本来想活下去
生活充实
not to maim yourselves.
不要伤害自己。
Look!
看！
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
Ohh...
哦...
Hey, what are you two
lazybones doing lying around?
嘿，你们两个是什么人
懒人躺着做什么？
There's a really
cool ramp down the hall.
确实有一个
沿着大厅很酷的坡道。
I got room for two more.
我还有空间容纳另外两个人。
What would Larry do?
拉里会怎么做？
I'll show you what
Larry would do, come here.
我会告诉你什么
拉里就行，过来吧。
...Come here,
I said.
...来这里，
我说。
Larry: Hey!
拉里：嘿！
Whoo, yeah.
哇，是啊。
SpongeBob: ♪ La, la, la, la... ♪
海绵宝宝：♪ 啦，啦，啦，啦……♪
I thought you left
your swimsuit at home?
我以为你离开了
你家里有泳衣吗？
No, I just didn't want
to get it all wrinkled up.
不，我只是不想
让一切都变得皱起来。
Last one in is a rotten egg.
最后一个是一个臭鸡蛋。
Rotten eggs?
臭鸡蛋？
: Bah...
: 呸...
Honey?
蜂蜜？
You're not using
that "tan accelerator"
again, are you?
你没有使用
那个“晒黑促进剂”
再说一次，你是吗？
Oh, don't pretend
you don't love it.
哦，别假装
你不喜欢它。
Man:
Good work, man.
男士：
干得好，伙计。
...I see you've
read my book?
...我看你已经
读我的书吗？
Craig Mammalton?
克雷格·马莫尔顿？
The tannest man on TV?
电视上最晒黑的男人？
None other.
没有别的。
Oh, look at those
gorgeous wrinkles.
哦，看看那些
华丽的皱纹。
What... These?
什么……这些？
Oh, and his skin.
哦，还有他的皮肤。
It's so leathery.
它是如此皮革。
Well, I don't mean
to brag, but, uh...
嗯，我的意思不是
吹牛，但是，呃...
Who's Craig mammalton?
克雷格·哺乳动物顿是谁？
You don't know
who Craig mammalton is?
你不知道
克雷格·哺乳动物顿是谁？
He's like  so  tan.
他晒得这么黑。
...Legend has it that
his tan is so deep
...传说
他的棕褐色很深
that even his bones
are a rich caramel brown.
甚至连他的骨头
是浓郁的焦糖棕色。
Wow.
哇。
His mother must
be  so  proud.
他的母亲必须
如此自豪。
Please, people, please.
拜托了，人们，拜托了。
There will be plenty of time
to admire my body this weekend
会有充足的时间
这个周末欣赏我的身体
at my annual summer shindig.
在我一年一度的夏季聚会上。
Wow, Patrick, an invitation
to our first summer shindig.
哇，帕特里克，邀请函
参加我们的第一次夏季聚会。
And here it is.
就是这样。
Can I help you
little fella?
我可以帮你吗
小家伙？
It seems to be stuck.
似乎被卡住了。
Yeah, I don't think
this is your type of party.
是的，我不认为
这就是您的聚会类型。
I don't wanna
embarrass you guys...
我不想
让你们尴尬了……
Hey, everyone,
check this out.
嘿，大家，
看看这个。
...But this party is
for the pigmentally  gifted.
...但是这个聚会是
对于有颜料天赋的人来说。
SpongeBob: Must be
this tan to enter.
海绵宝宝：一定是
这个晒黑进入。
And your skin is as light
and smooth as a...
你的皮肤同样轻盈
并且光滑如...
Well, as a baby's bottom.
嗯，就像婴儿的屁股一样。
Why, thank you.
为什么，谢谢。
We did put on a few extra
coats of sunscreen today.
我们确实多加了一些
今天涂了防晒霜。
In fact...
实际上...
It's time for another coat.
是时候再买一件外套了。
We've gotta look our best.
我们必须展现出最好的一面。
: Losers.
: 失败者。
you're not coming to my party
你不来参加我的聚会
...without a tan.
...没有晒黑。
There, now that we've turned
your rock into a tanning bed
现在我们已经转向了
把你的石头变成晒黑床
we're sure to get tan
enough for the party.
我们肯定会被晒黑
足够参加聚会了。
Let's just test it
out first to be sure.
我们来测试一下
首先确定一下。
Ooh.
哦。
Hooray.
万岁。
Me first,
Me first.
我先，
我先。
Ooh-hoo, Patrick,
how do you feel?
哦呼，帕特里克，
你感觉怎么样？
Like one of those
hip, young, old folks
就像其中之一
时髦的、年轻人的、老年人的
from a soda commercial.
来自苏打水广告。
It's radical.
这是激进的。
Radical.
激进的。
Drink it.
喝吧。
My turn.
轮到我了。
Remember, Patrick,
15 seconds exactly.
请记住，帕特里克，
正好15秒。
Got ya.
明白了。
15 seconds give or
take a few minutes.
15 秒给或
需要几分钟。
No-no, Patrick!
不，不，帕特里克！
15 seconds exactly.
正好15秒。
It's really important...
这真的很重要...
It's working.
它正在发挥作用。
Ok, Patrick, I'm done.
好吧，帕特里克，我完成了。
Patrick...  Patrick?
帕特里克……帕特里克？
Are you there?
你在吗？
...Patrick?
...帕特里克？
What?
什么？
Did somebody say something? Hm.
有人说了些什么吗？嗯。
Girls:  :
Hey, there.
女孩：：
嘿，在那里。
Is that tan
for us?
那是晒黑的吗
对我们来说？
What?
什么？
SpongeBob: Uh, Patrick?
海绵宝宝：呃，帕特里克？
It's time for me to get out.
我该出去了。
French Man: Two hours later.
法国人：两个小时后。
Girls:   Ohh...
女孩们：哦……
Do you really
have to go, Patrick?
你真的吗
得走了，帕特里克？
Afraid so.
恐怕是这样。
Bye, girls.
再见，女孩们。
All: Bye, Pat.
全体：再见，帕特。
Girl: Oh, he's
so leathery.
女孩：哦，他是
如此皮革般。
Well, Patrick, how do I look?
好吧，帕特里克，我看起来怎么样？
Patrick: Ahh!
帕特里克：啊！
Oh, it's you.
哦，是你。
You don't look too good.
你看起来不太好。
What, what,
what do you mean?
什么，什么，
你是什么意思？
See for yourself.
你自己看看吧。
I must've been under
the tanning machine too long.
我一定是在
晒黑机时间太长。
Ew, what are
you gonna do?
呃，什么是
你要做什么？
I'll ask Squidward.
我去问问章鱼哥。
He's always so helpful.
他总是那么乐于助人。
He'll know what to do.
他会知道该怎么做。
SpongeBob:
Hi, Squidward.
海绵宝宝：
嗨，章鱼哥。
What is it now sponge... Ahh!
现在海绵是什么……啊！
Ghost!
鬼！
I'm sorry I was so mean to
you while you were alive.
抱歉我太刻薄了
你活着的时候。
Please don't haunt me.
请不要困扰我。
Oh, I'm not a ghost, Squidward.
哦，我不是幽灵，章鱼哥。
: Bah...
: 呸...
I used Patrick's tanning booth
and I stayed under too long.
我用过帕特里克的晒黑亭
我在水下呆得太久了。
: Ha,
ha, ha, ha, ha.
：哈，
哈哈哈。
Oh, this is
too precious.
哦，这是
太珍贵了。
You're sun bleached.
你被太阳晒白了。
Looks like you won't
be at the party.
看来你不会
参加聚会。
Squidward: Ha,
ha, ha, ha.
章鱼哥：哈，
哈哈哈。
Sun bleached.
太阳晒白了。
Now I'll never get
into that party.
现在我永远也得不到
进入那个聚会。
Hey, that's
quitter talk, mister.
嘿，那是
放弃谈话，先生。
You're going to
that party tonight.
你将会
今晚的那个聚会。
What you need...
你需要什么...
is a makeover.
是一次改头换面。
Hmm... Hm.
嗯……嗯。
A little kelp jerky?
一点海带干？
Open wide.
敞开。
SpongeBob: Ah, ah?
海绵宝宝：啊啊？
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
I look...  Amazing.
我看起来……太棒了。
Time to go to the party.
是时候去参加聚会了。
Aw, what a cute
"wittle" baby.
噢，多么可爱啊
“机灵”宝宝。
Coochie coochie...
库奇库奇...
Ah, you...
啊，你...
Well, hey, buddy.
嗯，嘿，伙计。
You look like you
could use an ice cream.
你看起来像你
可以用冰淇淋。
Oh, yeah, that hit the spot.
哦，是的，这恰到好处。
Patrick: One carmel
sundae, please.
帕特里克：一卡梅尔
圣代，请。
Oh, I think you'll
have to go to the
party without me, Patrick.
哦，我想你会
必须去
没有我的派对，帕特里克。
There's just no way I can get
that Golden Brown in time.
我就是没有办法得到
及时的金棕色。
But that's no reason
you shouldn't go... Ow!
但这不是理由
你不应该去……噢！
Patrick,
why did you...
帕特里克，
你为什么...
No, really, Patrick,
why did you...
不，真的，帕特里克，
你为什么...
Ugh, I feel sticky.
呃，我感觉很粘。
Take a look.
看看吧。
Whoo!
呼！
Thanks,
Patrick...
谢谢，
帕特里克...
Uh, I'm stuck.
呃，我被困住了。
Craig: Nice job, ma'am.
克雷格：干得好，女士。
Join the party.
加入聚会。
Ahem, but, uh...
咳咳，但是，呃...
The baby's gonna
have to wait outside.
宝宝会的
必须在外面等待。
But he's the perfect shade
of "tropical toddler".
但他是完美的阴影
“热带幼儿”。
Yes, but...
是的，但是……
Tyler, how could you?
泰勒，你怎么可以？
Now don't worry, ma'am.
现在不用担心，女士。
He can wait out here
with the other rejects.
他可以在这里等
与其他拒绝。
Oh, no tears, son,
we'll get in next year.
哦，没有眼泪，儿子，
我们明年就会进去。
Next?
下一个？
Hey, hey...
: Hey-hey-Hey.
嘿嘿...
: 嘿嘿嘿。
Looks like you
two took my advice.
看起来像你
两个接受了我的建议。
Nice job, gentlemen
干得好，先生们
Come on in.
进来吧。
Craig: All right,
party people.
克雷格：好吧，
党的人。
It's time to
roll out the portables.
是时候了
推出便携式设备。
Oh, no,
caramel hardening.
哦，不，
焦糖硬化。
Got to get out of here.
必须离开这里。
Patrick?
帕特里克？
What?
什么？
Can I get a little
help here?
我可以得到一点吗
在这里帮忙？
Oh, sure thing, pal.
哦，当然可以，朋友。
Hey, everybody,
make some room.
嘿，大家，
腾出一些空间。
The floor's all yours.
地板都是你的了。
Knock 'em dead, kid.
把他们打死吧，孩子。
No, Patrick, I...  .
不，帕特里克，我……
So bright.
如此明亮。
Honey, look away.
亲爱的，把目光移开。
SpongeBob:
Eh, heh-heh.
海绵宝宝：
呃，呵呵。
: Nice job.
: 干得好。
Australian Fish: Your
hideously white skin
澳大利亚鱼：您的
皮肤白得可怕
just ruined the party-
look at you.
刚刚毁了聚会——
看看你。
...Do you hug your
mother with that skin?
...你拥抱你吗
妈妈有那种皮肤吗？
Can you believe this
guy crashed your party?
你能相信吗
那家伙破坏了你的聚会？
Craig?
克雷格？
I have seen this
only one other time.
我见过这个
只有一次。
It's the ultimate tan.
这是终极晒黑。
He's...
他是...
...Sun bleached.
...阳光漂白了。
Sun bleached?
太阳晒白了？
This young man...
这个年轻人...
this young  hero
这位年轻的英雄
should be praised
for his dedication
应该受到赞扬
为了他的奉献
to "tan-liness."
到“晒黑”。
Hooray.
万岁。
If you guys are feelin' it
如果你们感觉到了
we should all follow
in his footsteps.
我们都应该遵循
按照他的脚步。
Craig: Frankie, crank it up.
克雷格：弗兰基，加大力度。
French Man: Two hours later.
法国人：两个小时后。
But Patrick,
do you think maybe
但是帕特里克，
你认为也许
too much sun
is a bad thing?
太多阳光
是坏事吗？
Patrick: Whatever.
帕特里克：不管怎样。
I just go
with the flow.
我就走
随着流量。